all right
[Music]
body fat is probably the most highly
vascularized tissue in the body meaning
has the most blood vessels in fact each
individual fat cell surrounded by an
extensive network of tiny blood vessels
and since the formation of these blood
vessels appears to play a critical role
in fatty tissue growth and reduction the
regulation of angiogenesis the blood
vessel formation process May contribute
to weight gain and weight loss
so researchers tried injecting
anti-angiogenic drugs into overfed lab
animals and were able to induce profound
weight loss in mice as well as in
non-human primates which is how
scientists often refer to monkeys
the problem is that anti-angiogenic
drugs can cause a variety of rare but
fatal side effects we may be willing to
accept those risks in the context of
cancer treatment but when it comes to
cancer prevention or obesity
anti-angiogenic diets would seem a safer
bet not to mention cheaper
anti-angiogenic drugs can cost six
thousand dollars per dose
so which foods are the most
anti-angiogenic it's interesting how
they figured out that dietary components
could be anti-angiogenic at all
realizing that those eating plant-based
diets were protected from diseases of
excess angiogenesis like cancer diabetic
vision loss researchers took a group of
plant-based eaters and started pitting
various components of their urine
against the growth of human blood vessel
cells harvested from discarded umbilical
cords the concentration of
phytonutrients in the urine of
vegetarians can be 30 times higher than
that of the general population using
this method they identified a number of
natural
anti-angiogenic compounds in our diet
the question then became could the
levels required to block angiogenesis in
a Petri dish be reached in the
bloodstream after eating a meal the
answer researchers soon realized is yes
anti-angiogenic concentrations of
broccoli compounds can be reached in the
bloodstream within an hour eating less
than three quarters of a cup of broccoli
soup so these are totally doable kinds
of quantities you'll note most of these
compounds may be cleared from our body
within six hours though and fall back to
nearly zero within 24 hours so we should
strive to eat cruciferous vegetables at
least once a day
anti-angiogenic concentrations of
beta-cryptazanthin can be reached within
hours of eating two cups of red flesh
papaya one and a quarter cup of boiled
onions may get you an anti-angiogenic
dose of quercetin circulating your blood
in less than an hour
the level of protective soybean
compounds that may be necessary has been
found in the bloodstream of those eating
ordinary Japanese diets now I'm not
dreaming up some sort of broccoli papaya
onion tofu casserole these are just
examples showing
anti-angiogenic concentrations can be
achieved within your bloodstream after
eating reasonable serving sizes in
general the most concentrated dietary
sources of polyphenols that classify the
nutrients containing many of the
anti-angiogenic compounds discovered to
date are herbs and spices
the only others to place in the top ten
out of more than 450 Foods tested were
berries cocoa powder and ground flax
seeds on a per serving basis most of the
top contenders are berries with
artichokes leading the vegetables and
whole grain Rye leaving the grains
ironically yogurt is a leading Source in
the United States but only because most
are fruit flavored with many containing
berries as ingredients whereas even
plain soy yogurt makes it into the top
25.
for cancer prevention researchers
suggest the constant consumption of
anti-angiogenic foods do we have
evidence that it's having an effect well
based on the analysis of more than a
thousand tumors from one of Harvard's
studies on male health professionals men
eating the most tomato products had
significantly less angiogenesis within
their tumor which then appeared to
translate into a reduced risk of fatal
disease yeah but with the same
anti-angiogenic potential of fruits and
vegetables also help keep our bellies
from growing there's only one way to
find out
a meta-analysis more than a dozen
randomized controlled Trials of fruits
and vegetable interventions for
overweight individuals found six extra
pounds of weight loss but that could be
from a whole variety of factors like
decreased calorie density from the fiber
and water content but maybe
angiogenesis inhibition is playing a
role
I originally planned on including a
section on angiogenesis and how not to
diet but only one to include proven
mechanisms of weight loss so it's not in
the book I thought it's so interesting I
made these two videos about it
oh
thank you